=Within The Grip=
=그립 내부=
=Episode 5=
=에피소드 5=
(You're Such a Great Actor)
(당신은 정말 훌륭한 배우입니다)
(Fufeng Pavilion)
(푸펑 파빌리온)
Now let me teach you how to speak like Zhaoxi.
이제 가르쳐 줄게 Zhaoxi처럼 말하는 방법.
Keep your voice light, not too deep.
너무 깊지 않게 목소리를 가볍게 유지하세요.
Part your lips slowly.
천천히 입술을 벌리세요.
Why don't you
Why don't you
start by calling me "dear"?
나를 "여보"라고 부르는 것부터 시작할까요?
Dear.
에게.
Wrong.
잘못된.
That's right.
좋아요.
Keep practicing.
계속 연습하세요.
(Virtue of Heaven and Earth)
(천지의 덕)
(Yuluo.)
(율루오.)
(If I had competed to be the family head instead of pursuing martial arts,)
(내가 가장이 되기 위해 경쟁했다면 무술을 추구하는 대신)
(would things have been different between us?)
(사물이 있을까? 우리 사이는 달라졌나요?)
♪Willows sway in the twilight breeze♪
♪버드나무가 황혼의 미풍에 흔들리네요♪
♪Old dreams flow like melodious poetry♪
♪오래된 꿈은 아름다운 시처럼 흐른다♪
♪Memories fade like the passing years♪
♪기억은 세월이 흐르듯 흐려진다♪
♪The past events leave us confused♪
♪과거의 사건은 우리를 혼란스럽게 합니다♪
♪Prosperity fades like dreams♪
♪번영은 꿈처럼 사라져 버립니다♪
♪Affection lingers, unforgettable♪
♪애정은 잊혀지지 않습니다♪
♪Ink-stained scrolls recall bygones♪
♪잉크 묻은 두루마리는 과거를 회상합니다♪
♪Each stroke holds a thought♪
♪획 하나하나에 생각이 담겨있습니다♪
♪Prosperity fades like dreams♪
♪번영은 꿈처럼 사라져 버립니다♪
♪With nothing but memories left♪
♪추억밖에 남지 않은 채로♪
(Now, I have to watch you marry someone else.)
(이제 지켜봐야지 다른 사람과 결혼하세요.)
(You only met him a few days ago.)
(당신은 그 사람을 만난 지 며칠밖에 안 됐어요.)
(Are you truly fond of him?)
(정말 그 사람을 좋아하시나요?)
I didn't sleep well last night.
어젯밤에 잠을 잘 못 잤어요.
Those assassins chased me all the way to the Gu Mansion.
그 암살자들이 날 쫓아왔어 구맨션까지 가는 길.
Luckily, the guards discovered them and saved me in time.
다행히 경비병이 발견해 제 시간에 나를 구해주었습니다.
You must have been startled.
당신은 깜짝 놀랐을 것입니다.
It's alright, but I've been thinking.
괜찮아요. 하지만 생각해 봤어요.
I'm afraid someone did this on purpose.
누군가 고의로 이런 짓을 했을까봐 두렵습니다.
They think I paid off those assassins to stage this act.
사람들은 내가 그 암살자들에게 돈을 줬다고 생각해요 이 행위를 무대에 올리기 위해.
What makes you say that?
왜 그런 말을 하게 됐나요?
I intended to bring those assassins
난 그 암살자들을 데려오려고 했어
and talk to you about what to do.
그리고 어떻게 해야 할지 이야기해 보세요.
But Chaosheng stopped me before I even left.
하지만 Chaosheng이 날 막았어 내가 떠나기도 전에.
I'm not sure if I should say this.
이런 말을 해야 할지 모르겠습니다.
What do you think about Zhaoxi being attacked?
어떻게 생각하세요? Zhaoxi가 공격당했다고요?
Do you really believe that Zhaoxi ran into bandits?
당신은 정말로 믿습니까? Zhaoxi가 도둑을 만났다고?
Xuanji.
Xuanji.
It's only you and me here.
여기에는 당신과 나뿐이에요.
Feel free to speak your mind.
자유롭게 마음을 말해보세요.
Zhaoxi rarely goes out. Why did he leave the city that day?
Zhaoxi는 거의 외출하지 않습니다. 그는 그날 왜 그 도시를 떠났는가?
I found it suspicious and dug into it.
나는 그것이 의심스러워서 파헤쳐 보았다.
It turns out that Chaosheng didn't return those days.
그것은 밝혀졌다 그 당시 Chaosheng은 돌아 오지 않았습니다.
He met Zhaoxi after Father arranged for your wedding.
그는 아버지가 주선한 후 Zhaoxi를 만났습니다. 당신의 결혼식을 위해.
You don't look surprised. So you know this all along.
당신은 놀란 것 같지 않습니다. 그래서 당신은 이것을 내내 알고 있습니다.
Right, you're about to lead the Xuanji Pavilion.
그렇죠, 곧 그럴 거예요 쉬안지 파빌리온(Xuanji Pavilion)을 이끄세요.
Such a small matter wouldn't escape your notice.
이런 사소한 일 당신의 통지를 피하지 않을 것입니다.
However, there's one thing you certainly don't know.
그런데 한 가지가 있어요. 당신은 확실히 모릅니다.
Chaosheng once sent a famous assassin to kill Zhaoxi.
Chaosheng이 한 번 보냈습니다. Zhaoxi를 죽이는 유명한 암살자.
Watch your words.
당신의 말을 조심하십시오.
I heard you visited the assassin Leng Yan.
방문하셨다고 들었어요 암살자 Leng Yan.
But by the time you arrived, he was already dead.
하지만 당신이 도착했을 때, 그는 이미 죽어 있었습니다.
But the person who silenced him didn't know he had a mistress.
하지만 그를 침묵시킨 사람은 그에게 여주인이 있는 줄 몰랐다.
She wasn't home and escaped the ordeal.
그녀는 집에 없었고 시련을 피했습니다.
I felt sorry for her and kept her at Nichang Workshop.
나는 그녀에게 안타까움을 느꼈다 그녀를 Nichang Workshop에 보관했습니다.
If you want to meet her,
그녀를 만나고 싶다면
I can bring her over to take your measures these days.
내가 그녀를 데려올 수 있어요 요즘 조치를 취하기 위해.
Since you have doubts, why don't you inform the family head
의심이 드시니까,
or the authorities?
가장에게 알리는 게 어때?
The authorities concluded
아니면 당국?
that Zhaoxi was attacked by the bandits.
당국은 결론을 내렸다
Father can't be worried about these matters at this moment.
Zhaoxi가 도적의 공격을 받았다는 것입니다.
I was restless after the attack yesterday.
아버지는 걱정하지 않으셔도 돼요 지금 이 문제에 대해.
If that person is trying to be the family head,
나는 불안했다 어제 공격 이후.
then Zhaoxi and I won't be the last victims.
그 사람이라면
Chaosheng wants to be the family head.
가족의 가장이 되려고 노력하고 있어요
And what about you?
그럼 자오시와 나는 마지막 희생자는 아닐 것이다.
Chaosheng has managed the shops for years.
Chaosheng은 가장이 되고 싶어합니다.
He's quite recognized, but outsiders are clueless.
그리고 당신은 어떻습니까?
Everyone in the family knows that the Xuanji Pavilion is the core.
Chaosheng은 수년 동안 상점을 관리했습니다.
Whoever wants to be the new family head needs your support.
그 사람 꽤 인정받는데, 하지만 외부인들은 전혀 모른다.
I know you suspect that I sent assassins for Zhaoxi.
가족 모두가 아는 사실이다 Xuanji Pavilion이 핵심입니다.
But if it were me,
새로운 가장이 되고 싶은 사람 여러분의 지원이 필요합니다.
I would never attempt something so clumsy.
나는 당신이 의심하는 것을 알고 내가 Zhaoxi를 위해 암살자를 보냈다는 것입니다.
There are ways to kill someone without getting noticed, right?
하지만 만약 나라면
For example,
나는 절대로 너무 서투른 일을 시도하십시오.
with poison.
사람을 죽이는 방법도 있다 눈치채지도 못한 채, 그렇죠?
What makes you say that?
예를 들어
You're an expert in the art of poisoning.
독으로.
The poisons and antidotes you develop are priceless.
왜 그런 말을 하게 됐나요?
Leng Yan died from a strange poison with a smile on his face
당신은 전문가입니다 중독의 기술에서.
and blood oozing out from seven orifices.
독극물과 해독제 당신이 개발하는 것은 매우 귀중합니다.
That reminds me of your Laughing Netherworld.
Leng Yan은 이상한 독으로 사망했습니다. 얼굴에 미소를 띠고
It seems the culprit is determined to throw this mud at me.
그리고 피가 새어나온다 일곱 개의 구멍에서.
Master Chaosheng barged in Fufeng Pavilion. He's with Master Zhaoxi now.
그게 생각나네 당신의 Laughing Netherworld의.
What brings you here today, Chaosheng?
오늘은 무슨 일로 여기까지 왔나요, Chaosheng?
I haven't been well after that heavy snow.
나는 잘 지내지 못했다 그 폭설 이후.
So I invited Physician Li over. He can also check on you.
그래서 나는 리 의사를 초대했습니다. 그는 또한 당신을 확인할 수도 있습니다.
I hope you recover soon.
빨리 회복하시길 바랍니다.
That would put my mind at ease.
그러면 마음이 편해질 것 같아요.
Well, thank you, Chaosheng.
그렇군요, 고마워요, 차오셩님.
(Light steps, calluses in the palm.)
(가벼운 발걸음, 손바닥의 굳은 살.)
(He is no ordinary physician.)
(그는 평범한 의사가 아니다.)
(He's more like a martial artist.)
(그는 무술가에 가깝습니다.)
Well?
잘?
Just as you predicted.
당신이 예측한 대로요.
Both his old ailments and new injuries need careful recuperation.
그의 오래된 질병과 새로운 부상 모두 세심한 회복이 필요합니다.
You may leave.
떠날 수도 있습니다.
Understood.
이해했다.
The court has ordered to eradicate the bandits outside the city.
법원은 근절하라고 명령했다. 도시 밖의 도적들.
Do you remember anything about the bandits who attacked you?
기억나는 게 있나요? 당신을 공격한 도적들에 대해서요?
It was chaotic.
그것은 혼란스러웠다.
I can't remember much.
별로 기억이 나지 않습니다.
Why aren't you wearing that jade pendant
왜 그 옥 펜던트를 착용하지 않았나요
you have had since childhood?
어릴 때부터 있었나요?
I suppose it was lost while I was under attack.
잃어버린 것 같아요 내가 공격을 받고 있는 동안.
Master Chaosheng, Prince Rui brought a masterpiece to enjoy with you.
조성대사, 루이왕자가 데려왔다 당신과 함께 즐길 수 있는 걸작.
He's heading straight here.
그는 곧장 여기로 향하고 있습니다.
Should we...?
우리는...?
You are in high spirits.
당신은 기분이 좋습니다.
I'm surprised to see you here, Chaosheng.
나는 놀랐다 여기서 만나요, 차오셍.
But the family head just sent a physician over.
하지만 가장은 방금 의사를 보냈어요.
And you brought another physician.
그리고 당신은 다른 의사를 데려왔습니다.
If others learn about it, I fear it may spark gossip
다른 사람들이 그 사실을 알게 된다면, 소문이 촉발될까 봐
that you distrust the physician sent by the family head.
당신이 의사를 불신한다는 것 가장이 보냈습니다.
Since you won't accept my goodwill,
당신이 내 호의를 받아들이지 않으니,
let's say I've overstepped.
내가 너무 지나쳤다고 해보자.
We can't keep Prince Rui waiting. Bring him in.
루이왕자를 기다리게 할 수는 없습니다. 그를 데려오세요.
Understood.
이해했다.
Dear.
에게.
Chaosheng, Zhaoxi hasn't fully recovered.
차오성, Zhaoxi는 완전히 회복되지 않았습니다.
Please excuse us from joining you. We won't see you out.
함께하지 못함을 양해해 주시기 바랍니다. 우리는 당신을 보지 않을 것입니다.
Your acting has truly reached new heights.
당신의 연기는 정말 새로운 높이에 도달했습니다.
I'm deeply impressed.
나는 깊은 인상을 받았습니다.
I'm still having a cold.
아직도 감기에 걸렸어요.
You're burning.
당신은 불타고 있습니다.
Rest well.
잘 쉬세요.
Master, Gu Zhaoxi is indeed chronically ill.
구자오시 선생님 실제로 만성질환이다.
Nothing unusual.
특이한 것은 없습니다.
(Vast Mind, Eternal Will)
(광활한 마음, 영원한 의지)
Master, the east wind has arrived.
선생님, 동풍이 왔습니다.
If anyone comes, tell them I'm unwell
누가 오면 몸이 안 좋다고 전해줘
and can't see them.
그리고 그들을 볼 수 없습니다.
Master, are you truly going?
선생님, 정말 가시나요?
Of course.
물론.
But
하지만
I'm not sure if my "husband"...
내 "남편"이...
I've sent people to investigate his former residence.
사람들을 보냈어요 그의 전 거주지를 조사하기 위해.
His connections are simple, and the facts check out.
그의 인맥은 간단하다. 그리고 사실을 확인해 보세요.
Master, do you still have concerns?
선생님, 아직도 고민이 있으신가요?
He's way too simple,
그 사람은 너무 단순해
which raises concerns.
이는 우려를 낳는다.
We can't keep Prince Rui waiting. Bring him in.
루이왕자를 기다리게 할 수는 없습니다. 그를 데려오세요.
Understood.
이해했다.
Find out if he knows Prince Rui.
그가 루이 왕자를 아는지 알아보세요.
Xuan Qing.
쉬안칭.
Make a cold-dispelling medicine for him.
그를 위해 감기약을 만들어 주세요.
Understood.
이해했다.
Both Qing Que and Xuan Wu are finally away on missions.
Qing Que와 Xuan Wu 모두 드디어 임무를 수행하러 떠났습니다.
Everyone went drinking except for us.
우리 빼고 다들 술을 마시러 갔어요.
And we need to patrol.
그리고 순찰도 해야 해요.
Enough, everyone's gone. Let's hope nothing goes wrong.
이제 모두가 사라졌습니다. 아무 일도 일어나지 않기를 바랍니다.
Check the Xuanji Pavilion.
Xuanji Pavilion을 확인하세요.
The Earth Unit did a great job in the challenge.
지구부대가 큰 일을 해냈습니다 도전에.
This junior reminds me of the former Pavilion Master's demeanor.
이 후배가 생각나네요 전 파빌리온 마스터의 태도.
It appears this Heaven mission
천국의 임무인 것 같습니다
still requires your handling.
여전히 처리가 필요합니다.
It's not time yet.
아직은 시간이 아닙니다.
Xuanji Pavilion
쉬안지 파빌리온
collects tips rather than carrying out assassinations.
팁을 모으는 것보다 암살을 수행합니다.
To bring back the tips,
팁을 다시 가져오려면
staying resolved often outweighs defeating enemies.
결심을 유지하다 종종 적을 물리치는 것보다 더 중요합니다.
(Earth)
(지구)
Gu Yuluo of Earth Unit requests to take on the Heaven mission.
지구 유닛의 구위뤄 천국 임무를 맡아달라고 요청합니다.
Hurry up. Search.
서둘러요. 찾다.
Master.
주인.
Search over there. Don't let them escape.
저기서 검색해 보세요. 그들이 탈출하도록 놔두지 마세요.
Find him first. I'll handle them.
먼저 그를 찾아보세요. 내가 처리할게요.
Dear.
에게.
♪Willows sway in the twilight breeze♪
♪버드나무가 황혼의 미풍에 흔들리네요♪
♪Ancient alleys guard time's secrets♪
♪고대 골목은 시간의 비밀을 지킨다♪
♪Bluestones bear life's imprints♪
♪블루스톤에는 생명의 흔적이 새겨져 있습니다♪
♪Falling petals, endless longing♪
♪떨어지는 꽃잎, 끝없는 그리움♪
♪Longing lingers within my heart♪
♪그리움은 내 마음속에 남아있습니다♪
♪Zither strings sigh for the sorrow parting♪
♪치터 현의 한숨 슬픈 이별을 위해♪
♪Past tales nest in my soul♪
♪과거 이야기가 내 영혼에 둥지를 틀고 있습니다♪
♪Affection lingers, unforgettable♪
♪애정은 잊혀지지 않습니다♪
♪Ink-stained scrolls recall bygones♪
♪잉크 묻은 두루마리는 과거를 회상합니다♪
♪Each stroke holds a thought♪
♪획 하나하나에 생각이 담겨있습니다♪
♪Prosperity fades like dreams♪
♪번영은 꿈처럼 사라져 버립니다♪
♪Past tales nest in my soul♪
♪과거 이야기가 내 영혼에 둥지를 틀고 있습니다♪
♪Affection lingers, unforgettable♪
♪애정은 잊혀지지 않습니다♪
♪Ink-stained scrolls recall bygones♪
♪잉크 묻은 두루마리는 과거를 회상합니다♪
♪Each stroke holds a thought♪
♪획 하나하나에 생각이 담겨있습니다♪
♪Prosperity fades like dreams♪
♪번영은 꿈처럼 사라져 버립니다♪
♪Past tales nest in my soul♪
♪과거 이야기가 내 영혼에 둥지를 틀고 있습니다♪